Combined Cycle Power Plant Data Set 
Download: Data Folder, Data Set Description

Abstract: The dataset contains 9568 data points collected from a Combined Cycle Power Plant over 6 years (2006-2011), when the plant was set to work with full load.

Data Set Characteristics:  

Multivariate

Number of Instances:

9568

Area:

Computer

Attribute Characteristics:

Real

Number of Attributes:

4

Date Donated

2014-03-26

Associated Tasks:

Regression

Missing Values?

N/A

Number of Web Hits:

91902


Source:

Pınar Tüfekci, Çorlu Faculty of Engineering, Namık Kemal University, TR-59860 Çorlu, Tekirdağ, Turkey
Email: ptufekci '@' nku.edu.tr

Heysem Kaya, Department of Computer Engineering, Boğaziçi University, TR-34342, Beşiktaş, İstanbul, Turkey
Email: heysem '@' boun.edu.tr


Data Set Information:

The dataset contains 9568 data points collected from a Combined Cycle Power Plant over 6 years (2006-2011), when the power plant was set to work with full load. Features consist of hourly average ambient variables Temperature (T), Ambient Pressure (AP), Relative Humidity (RH) and Exhaust Vacuum (V) to predict the net hourly electrical energy output (EP) of the plant.
A combined cycle power plant (CCPP) is composed of gas turbines (GT), steam turbines (ST) and heat recovery steam generators. In a CCPP, the electricity is generated by gas and steam turbines, which are combined in one cycle, and is transferred from one turbine to another. While the Vacuum is colected from and has effect on the Steam Turbine, he other three of the ambient variables effect the GT performance.
For comparability with our baseline studies, and to allow 5x2 fold statistical tests be carried out, we provide the data shuffled five times. For each shuffling 2-fold CV is carried out and the resulting 10 measurements are used for statistical testing.
We provide the data both in .ods and in .xlsx formats.


Attribute Information:

Features consist of hourly average ambient variables 
- Temperature (T) in the range 1.81°C and 37.11°C,
- Ambient Pressure (AP) in the range 992.89-1033.30 milibar,
- Relative Humidity (RH) in the range 25.56% to 100.16%
- Exhaust Vacuum (V) in teh range 25.36-81.56 cm Hg
- Net hourly electrical energy output (EP) 420.26-495.76 MW
The averages are taken from various sensors located around the plant that record the ambient variables every second. The variables are given without normalization.


Relevant Papers:

Pınar Tüfekci, Prediction of full load electrical power output of a base load operated combined cycle power plant using machine learning methods, International Journal of Electrical Power & Energy Systems, Volume 60, September 2014, Pages 126-140, ISSN 0142-0615, [Web Link]. ([Web Link])

Heysem Kaya, Pınar Tüfekci , Sadık Fikret Gürgen: Local and Global Learning Methods for Predicting Power of a Combined Gas & Steam Turbine, Proceedings of the International Conference on Emerging Trends in Computer and Electronics Engineering ICETCEE 2012, pp. 13-18 (Mar. 2012, Dubai)

